<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>How-To Archives - CyberSTAR</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-types/how-to/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-types/how-to/</link>
	<description>CyberSTAR</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 13:59:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How to Browse Incognito</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-browse-incognito/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 09:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles#038;p=914</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The browser you are using to access the Internet keeps a lot of information about you and your online activity. Most browsers store cookies which track your browsing habits and often provide this information to third parties. Browsers also keep detailed lists of websites you visit, your search records, downloads, and other information. While most [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-browse-incognito/">How to Browse Incognito</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The browser you are using to access the Internet keeps a lot of information about you and your online activity. Most browsers store cookies which track your browsing habits and often provide this information to third parties. Browsers also keep detailed lists of websites you visit, your search records, downloads, and other information.</p>
<p>While most of this data is used to improve your browsing experience and ensure that the ads you see are relevant to you, you never know exactly how companies that collect this information use it. If you do not want your browser to retain your cookies, browsing history, search records, and downloads, you could use it in an incognito or private mode. Available on all popular browsers, this feature also prevents others who use the same computer from being able to see the list of websites you visited and files you downloaded. So, <strong>always use incognito mode on public or shared computers</strong> to enhance your privacy.</p>
<p>Remember that <strong>incognito mode only prevents the browser from collecting and storing your browsing information</strong>. It does not make you anonymous online or prevent your employer, internet cafe, or internet service provider from seeing your traffic or, in some cases, recording your keystrokes.</p>
<h1>Turning incognito mode on</h1>
<h2>For Google Chrome (Desktop)</h2>
<ol>
<li>Click the Chrome menu button (three vertical dots in the top right corner)</li>
<li>Select <strong>New incognito window</strong>. A new Chrome window will open with the Incognito logo in the upper-left corner.</li>
<li>You can also use the shortcut Ctrl-Shift-N on Windows machines and Command-Shift-N on MacOS machines</li>
</ol>
<h2>For Google Chrome (Mobile)</h2>
<ol>
<li>Tap the Chrome menu button (three vertical dots to the right of the address bar on Android; three horizontal dots in bottom right corner on an Apple device).</li>
<li>Tap <strong>New Incognito Tab</strong>. A new tab will open and the Incognito logo will appear.</li>
</ol>
<h2>For Microsoft Edge (Desktop)</h2>
<p>You can open an InPrivate window (a Microsoft version of an incognito window) in different ways:</p>
<ul>
<li>Right-click the Microsoft Edge logo in the taskbar and select <strong>New InPrivate window</strong></li>
<li>In Microsoft Edge, right-click a link and select <strong>Open link in InPrivate window</strong></li>
<li>In Microsoft Edge, click <strong>Settings and more</strong> and select <strong>New InPrivate window</strong></li>
</ul>
<h2>For Mozilla Firefox (Desktop)</h2>
<p>There are two ways to start a private browsing session (the Firefox version of incognito mode) on a desktop computer:</p>
<ul>
<li>Tap the Firefox menu button (three horizontal lines in the top right corner) and select <strong>New Private Window</strong></li>
<li>Use the keyboard shortcut Ctrl-Shift-P on Windows machines and Command-Shift-P on MacOS machines</li>
</ul>
<h2>For Mozilla Firefox (Mobile)</h2>
<ol>
<li>To open a Private Tab in Firefox on your mobile device, tap the tab icon (a square with a number inside) at the bottom of the screen. The tab can be found next to the address bar on an Android device and at the bottom of the screen on an Apple device.</li>
<li>Tap the mask button to switch to Private Browsing;</li>
<li>Tap the <strong>+PRIVATE</strong> button on Android devices or the <strong>+</strong> icon on an Apple device to open a new Private Tab</li>
</ol>
<p>Mozilla now also offers Firefox Focus, a special version of the Firefox browser that automatically makes <em>all</em> browsing sessions incognito.</p>
<h2>For Safari (Desktop)</h2>
<p>There are two ways to start a private browsing session in Safari on your desktop:</p>
<ul>
<li>With Safari opened, click the “File” menu and select <strong>New Private Window</strong></li>
<li>Use the keyboard shortcut Command-Shift-N</li>
</ul>
<h2>For Safari (Mobile)</h2>
<ol>
<li>Open Safari on your iPhone or iPod</li>
<li>Tap the Tabs icon (two squares in the bottom right of the screen)</li>
<li>Tap the <strong>Tabs</strong> button (a number followed by the word “Tab” or “Tabs”) at the bottom of the screen</li>
</ol>
<p>Tap <strong>Private</strong>, then tap <strong>Done</strong>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-browse-incognito/">How to Browse Incognito</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Enhance Your Browsing Privacy</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-enhance-your-browsing-privacy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 09:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles#038;p=913</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Every time you surf the Internet, you leave traces that are recorded, analyzed and sometimes even sold to data brokers. The browser you are using to access the Internet collects and keeps a lot of information about you and your online activity. For starters, most browsers store cookies which track your browsing habits to save [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-enhance-your-browsing-privacy/">How to Enhance Your Browsing Privacy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every time you surf the Internet, you leave traces that are recorded, analyzed and sometimes even sold to data brokers. The browser you are using to access the Internet collects and keeps a lot of information about you and your online activity. For starters, most browsers store cookies which track your browsing habits to save you time and ensure that the ads you see are relevant to you. Browsers also keep detailed lists of websites you visit, your search records, downloads, and other information.</p>
<p>If you do not like the idea of companies collecting and using this information about you, follow these tips to enhance your privacy by limiting digital traces you leave while browsing the Internet.</p>
<h2>1. Use Firefox in Strict mode</h2>
<p>While all popular browsers have their pros and cons, not all of them do an equally good job at giving users the tools to control their browsing privacy. For users who care about their privacy, we recommend using Firefox by Mozilla with Enhanced Tracking Protection set to Strict. In this mode, Firefox blocks the creation of certain tracking cookies and other methods of identifying you. In addition to strict mode, you should consider setting your history setting to “Never remember”, which will automatically erase your browser history and delete all cookies, trackers, and cryptominers, making it virtually impossible for any website to track your browsing. Note that if you set your history to “Never remember,” you will have to re-login to every website every time you open the web browser.</p>
<p>When you install Firefox, its Enhanced Tracking Protection is set to Standard by default. Follow these steps to change this setting to Strict:</p>
<h3>Firefox on a desktop device</h3>
<ol>
<li>Click the shield icon to the left of the address bar on any website and select <strong>Protection Settings</strong>. This will open the Firefox Settings <strong>Privacy &amp; Security</strong> panel.</li>
<li>Under <strong>Enhanced Tracking Protection</strong>, select <strong>Strict</strong>.</li>
<li><em>OPTIONAL</em>: Under <strong>History</strong>, select <strong>Never remember history.</strong></li>
</ol>
<h3>Firefox on an Android device</h3>
<ol>
<li>Tap the menu button (three vertical dots to the right of the address bar);</li>
<li>Tap <strong>Settings </strong>in the menu panel;</li>
<li>Under <strong>Privacy and Security</strong>, tap <strong>Enhanced Tracking Protection</strong>.</li>
<li>Under <strong>Enhanced Tracking Protection</strong>, select <strong>Strict</strong>.</li>
<li><em>OPTIONAL:</em> Just below this, you can select <strong>Delete browsing data on quit. </strong>This will open a new menu. When you turn the radio button on, by default it will clear your history, cookies and all other data on exit. If you would like to <em>retain </em>your history, cookies, or any other piece of data, you can deselect it here.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Firefox on an iOS device</h3>
<ol>
<li>Tap the menu button (three horizontal bars at the bottom right on an iPhone or top right on an iPad);</li>
<li>Tap <strong>Settings</strong> in the menu panel;</li>
<li>Scroll down and, under PRIVACY, tap <strong>Tracking Protection</strong>;</li>
<li>Check that <strong>Enhanced Tracking Protection</strong> is enabled and, under PROTECTION LEVEL, select <strong>Strict</strong>.</li>
<li>NOTE: Firefox on iOS doesn’t have the “Delete browsing data on quit” option at last check. If you would like to prevent cookies and history from being stored on your mobile phone, you should consider Firefox Focus for iOS instead.</li>
</ol>
<h2>2. Install an ad blocker</h2>
<p>In addition to using Firefox with Enhanced Tracking Protection set to Strict, we recommend installing either Privacy Badger or uBlockOrigin, reliable browser add-ons that block malicious ads, trackers and malware sites. These add-ons are also available for other browsers.</p>
<p>Follow these steps to install Privacy Badger or uBlockOrigin on your browser:</p>
<h3>Mozilla Firefox</h3>
<ol>
<li>Visit the Mozilla Firefox Add-ons page, find <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/privacy-badger17" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Privacy Badger</a> or <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/ublock-origin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">uBlock Origin</a>, and click <strong>Add to Firefox</strong>.</li>
<li>When prompted, click <strong>Add</strong> to confirm.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Google Chrome</h3>
<ol>
<li>Visit the Chrome Web Store, find <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/privacy-badger/pkehgijcmpdhfbdbbnkijodmdjhbjlgp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Privacy Badger</a> or <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ublock-origin/cjpalhdlnbpafiamejdnhcphjbkeiagm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">uBlock Origin</a>, and click <strong>Add to Chrome</strong>.</li>
<li>When prompted, click <strong>Add</strong> to confirm.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Microsoft Edge</h3>
<ol>
<li>Visit the Microsoft Edge Add-ons Store, find <a href="https://microsoftedge.microsoft.com/addons/detail/privacy-badger/mkejgcgkdlddbggjhhflekkondicpnop" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Privacy Badger</a> or <a href="https://microsoftedge.microsoft.com/addons/detail/ublock-origin/odfafepnkmbhccpbejgmiehpchacaeak" target="_blank" rel="noopener">uBlock Origin</a>, and click <strong>Get</strong>.</li>
<li>When prompted, click <strong>Add extension</strong> to confirm.</li>
</ol>
<h2>3. Use incognito mode on shared computers</h2>
<p>One way to prevent a browser from storing your cookies, browsing history, search records, and downloads is to use it in an incognito or private mode. Available on all popular browsers, this feature prevents others who use the same computer from being able to see the list of websites you visited and files you downloaded. <strong>Always use incognito mode on public or shared computers</strong> to enhance your privacy. <a href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-browse-incognito/">Follow this guide</a> to start browsing incognito in whichever browser you are using.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-enhance-your-browsing-privacy/">How to Enhance Your Browsing Privacy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Chat Safely on Telegram</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-chat-safely-on-telegram/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 14:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles#038;p=466</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Despite its popularity in many countries, the messaging app Telegram is not as secure as most of its users think. For starters, regular Telegram chats are not end-to-end encrypted. While the app does offer a way for two people to chat through an end-to-end encrypted channel, this option is not default. Nor is it available [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-chat-safely-on-telegram/">How to Chat Safely on Telegram</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Despite its popularity in many countries, the messaging app Telegram is not as secure as most of its users think. For starters, regular Telegram chats are not end-to-end encrypted. While the app does offer a way for two people to chat through an end-to-end encrypted channel, this option is not default. Nor is it available for group chats. Telegram also has access to all of its users’ contacts and collects their metadata, including IP addresses and details about their devices. Finally, group chats and channels on Telegram are not particularly secure.</p>
<p>If you choose to stay on Telegram despite these risks, the safest way to message someone on the app is by using Secret Chats and setting the messages to self-destruct shortly after being read.</p>
<h2>Use Secret Chats</h2>
<p>The best way to protect your messages on Telegram is to use one-on-one Secret Chats that are end-to-end encrypted. As mentioned above, Secret Chats are not the default chat option on Telegram.</p>
<p>To start a Secret Chat, select the contact with whom you want to chat and open their profile by tapping the user’s image in the header.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-467 aligncenter" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user.jpg" alt="Choosing a user on Telegram for additional chat features." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Tap the three-dotted symbol next to the user’s name and select <strong>Start Secret Chat</strong> in the drop-down menu.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-469" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat.jpg" alt="Starting a secret chat with a friend on Telegram." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Confirm the selection by tapping <strong>Start</strong>. Once you start a Secret Chat, you will see a lock icon next to the user’s name in the header of the chat.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-470" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-confirm.jpg" alt="Confirm to start a secret chat on Telegram." width="1400" height="1400" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-confirm.jpg 1400w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-confirm-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-confirm-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-confirm-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-confirm-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-confirm-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1400px) 100vw, 1400px" /></p>
<h2>Set a self-destruct timer</h2>
<p>To set messages in a Secret Chat to self-destruct after being read, open the chat in which you want to use this option. What sets Secret Chats apart from regular chats on Instagram is a lock icon next to a user’s name, with both the lock symbol and the name appearing in green. Once you open the Secret Chat, tap the clock icon (in the Message field on iOS or top bar on Android).</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-471" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer.jpg" alt="Accessing the self-destruct timer on Telegram." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Select the desired time limit (from one second to one week). You will see the time limit set for the Secret Chat in the Message field. <img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-472" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct.jpg" alt="Setting the self-destruct time on Telegram." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>The self-destruct timer starts ticking the moment the message is displayed on the recipient’s screen (you will see two check marks under the message). As soon as the time runs out, the message disappears from both devices.</p>
<p>Please note that the self-destruct timer in Secret Chats will not have any effect on messages that were sent <strong>before</strong> the timer was set.</p>
<h2>Watch out for screenshots</h2>
<p>Telegram tries to detect screenshots and notify people using Secret Chats when a screenshot is taken.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-473" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot.jpg" alt="Screenshot detection and notification on Telegram." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Unfortunately, this function does not always work on some Android devices. You can also never know if a person you are messaging takes pictures of their screen with a different device. So, do not send private, confidential or sensitive messages to someone whom you do not trust fully.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-chat-safely-on-telegram/">How to Chat Safely on Telegram</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Send Vanishing Messages on WhatsApp</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-send-vanishing-messages-on-whatsapp/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 14:53:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles#038;p=475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>WhatsApp is generally a very secure messaging app that offers end-to-end encryption by default. However, it is less focused on user privacy than messengers like Signal or Wire. Although WhatsApp cannot access your encrypted messages, it collects a lot of metadata (the who, when and where information about your messaging) on you, as well as [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-send-vanishing-messages-on-whatsapp/">How to Send Vanishing Messages on WhatsApp</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WhatsApp is generally a very secure messaging app that offers end-to-end encryption by default. However, it is less focused on user privacy than messengers like Signal or Wire. Although WhatsApp cannot access your encrypted messages, it collects a lot of metadata (the who, when and where information about your messaging) on you, as well as your contacts and information about your device. WhatsApp shares this information with its parent company Facebook. Facebook then uses this information for commercial purposes and shares it with partners. In the event of data breach, all of this sensitive data could be compromised.</p>
<p>If you choose to stay on WhatsApp despite these risks, the app offers a very reliable and secure messaging platform protected by end-to-end encryption. You can further protect your conversations and the files you share on the app by setting messages to disappear automatically and by sharing photos and videos that vanish as soon as they are seen by the recipient.</p>
<h2>Set messages to vanish</h2>
<p>You can set messages in an individual chat to disappear after seven days. If you enable this setting, WhatsApp will securely delete chats from your phone and that of the recipient seven days after they are sent. Unfortunately, the seven-day option is the only one that WhatsApp currently provides.</p>
<p>To enable disappearing messages in an individual WhatsApp chat, open the chat and tap the contact’s name. Scroll down and select <strong>Disappearing Messages</strong>. If prompted, tap <strong>Continue</strong> to confirm the selection.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-482" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend.jpg" alt="Selecting a friend and then scrolling down to find Disappearing Messages under Contact Info in Whatsapp." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-481" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info.jpg" alt="Disappearing Messages option under Contact Info in Whatsapp." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Select <strong>On</strong>. When you enable disappearing messages, you will see a notification in the chat. You will also see a clock icon displayed on the contact’s profile image.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-480" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages.jpg" alt="Enabling Disappearing Messages in Whatsapp." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Please note that enabling disappearing messages will not have any effect on messages that were sent <strong>before</strong> the setting was enabled. It is also worth remembering that disappearing messages will not prevent the person you are chatting with from forwarding your messages or keeping them by taking screenshots or saving media files.</p>
<h2>Using “view once” feature</h2>
<p>The “view once” feature allows you to set photos and videos to disappear after they are seen. This feature gives you more control over your privacy than when you send media files in a regular way. After the recipient opens the media file, it gets deleted as soon as they navigate away from it. If the recipient does not open the file, it expires and vanishes after two weeks.</p>
<p>You know that a message is a “view once” file when the preview is hidden and a large “1” is displayed instead. “View ones” media files cannot be shared or saved to a device.</p>
<p>To send a “view once” file, open an individual or group chat and tap <strong>Attach</strong> (a + icon on iPhone or a staple icon on an Android device). Select an existing photo or video on your device. Alternatively, you can tap <strong>Camera</strong> and take a photo or record a video that will not be saved on your device.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-479" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo.jpg" alt="Choosing a photo to send selecting the Photo and Video Library option in Whatsapp." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Tap “1” in the Message field. You will see a notification saying “Photo set to view once”, and the “1” icon in the message field will turn blue.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-478" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once.jpg" alt="Number 1 appearing as an indicator in the text box when a photo is set to view once before being sent in Whatsapp." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Tap <strong>Send</strong>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-477" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view.jpg" alt="How a photo that is set to view once appears with the number 1 appearing next to it in a Whatsapp chat." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>You will see an Opened receipt in the chat once the recipient has seen the photo or video.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-476" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened.jpg" alt="How a photo that is set to view once appears after viewed in a Whatsapp chat." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Please note that using the “view once” feature does not prevent the recipient from taking a screenshot or screen recording of the media file when it is first opened. So, do not send private, confidential or sensitive photos or videos to someone whom you do not trust fully.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-send-vanishing-messages-on-whatsapp/">How to Send Vanishing Messages on WhatsApp</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Not to Fall for Phishing</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-not-to-fall-for-phishing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 05:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles#038;p=456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Phishing scams are as old as the Internet itself and they are not going away. Fortunately, it is usually easy to avoid falling for phishing if you practice basic digital safety rules and use common sense. Follow these basic guidelines to keep yourself safe. 1. Remain skeptical Always remember that when something you are offered [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-not-to-fall-for-phishing/">How Not to Fall for Phishing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Phishing scams are as old as the Internet itself and they are not going away. Fortunately, it is usually easy to avoid falling for phishing if you practice basic digital safety rules and use common sense. Follow these basic guidelines to keep yourself safe.</p>
<h2>1. Remain skeptical</h2>
<p>Always remember that when something you are offered online seems too good to be true, it probably isn’t true at all. Scammers and criminals are very skillful at manipulating our emotions, particularly greed and curiosity. Would you like the latest iPhone for only $20? Would you like to earn a lot of money by trying all these free products that companies send to you for free? Would you like to know which of your classmates or coworkers is secretly into you? All you need to do to get these rewards is click a link, open an attachment or complete a form. Do not fall for this. You are smarter than that.</p>
<h2>2. Beware of attachments</h2>
<p>It is one of the most fundamental digital safety rules that you should never download or open attachments that arrive in emails, social media messages, or mobile texts from people you do not know or do not trust fully. Scammers and criminals are particularly fond of Word, Excel, PowerPoint and PDF attachments. If an email or any other type of message looks strange or suspicious to you, the best way to deal with it is by deleting it right away.</p>
<p>It is also worth remembering that even people you know and trust can have their email accounts compromised. So if you receive an unexpected email with an attachment from them, it is a good idea to check with the person who you think sent you the email before opening it.</p>
<h2>3. Check links before clicking</h2>
<p>It goes without saying that you should never click on links sent by people or organizations that you do not know or do not expect to be contacting you. You should also make it a habit to treat each single link you receive as a potential risk. When you get an alert from a colleague, your bank or the social media service you are using, do not click the link in the email. Hover your mouse over the link to see the full website address. This can help you decide whether or not you want to click that link. Alternatively, you can open a browser window and type of address directly into the URL field to make sure the site is real.</p>
<p>Before clicking on a link that you find even a tiny bit suspicious, scan it with a link scanner such as <a href="https://safeweb.norton.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Norton Safe Web</a> that lets you enter the URL of a suspicious link and check it for safety.</p>
<p>Use extra caution when dealing with shortened URL links. Always check the real URL link behind a shortened one. You can use a free online service such as <a href="https://unshorten.it/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UnshortenIt</a> to “decode” a shortened URL.</p>
<h2>4. Slow down to think</h2>
<p>One of the phishing tactics that criminals and scammers use particularly well involves creating a false sense of urgency by sending people requests with a tight deadline for action and sometimes punishment for failing to act fast. They may tell you to pay a fine for making an “error” in your latest tax return or face criminal prosecution. Or someone pretending to be your boss may demand that you wire money to a specific bank account or get fired.</p>
<p>Always treat “urgent” requests for information or financial transfers as highly suspicious. Would the tax authorities ever call on your mobile phone to demand that you pay a fine? Would your boss ever demand that you wire money to a bank account that you have never heard about? If something seems off, discuss it with people you trust, colleagues or a lawyer.</p>
<h2>5. Verify identity</h2>
<p>Always verify that people or organizations requesting information or financial transfers are those who they claim to be. Call them directly or get in touch via a secure messaging platform to double check. Remember that scammers are very skillful at impersonating people and they put a lot of effort and research into doing so.</p>
<h2>6. Keep your antivirus up to date</h2>
<p>Even if you are extremely cautious and practice perfect digital hygiene, you should always have antivirus and firewall running on all devices you are using. Make sure your antivirus is always up to date so it can deal with any new security threats. It is a good idea to set your critical software such as antivirus and operating system to update automatically.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-not-to-fall-for-phishing/">How Not to Fall for Phishing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Protect Yourself Against Malware</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-yourself-against-malware/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 05:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles#038;p=455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the most common ways hackers and criminals cause trouble online is by spreading malware. In addition to using common sense, follow these basic guidelines to protect yourself against malware. 1. Use antivirus software You should always have reliable antivirus software running on all devices you are using. This software is your main line [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-yourself-against-malware/">How to Protect Yourself Against Malware</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the most common ways hackers and criminals cause trouble online is by spreading malware. In addition to using common sense, follow these basic guidelines to protect yourself against malware.</p>
<h2>1. Use antivirus software</h2>
<p>You should always have reliable antivirus software running on all devices you are using. This software is your main line of defense against viruses and other types of malware. Make sure your antivirus is always up to date so it can deal with any new security threats.</p>
<p>Antivirus programs allow you to scan your entire device for malware. Make it a habit to run regular scans of your devices to catch malware early and prevent it from spreading. If you need to download something, make sure to use an antivirus program to scan the download for malware before opening it.</p>
<p>Windows comes with free and reliable antivirus software, Microsoft Defender, built-in. You can get Microsoft Defender to protect your device even better by <a title="How to Make Windows Defender More Secure" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-make-windows-defender-more-secure/">adjusting a few settings</a>.</p>
<h2>2. Keep your software and hardware up to date</h2>
<p>Malware infects your devices by finding and exploiting vulnerabilities in software. Hackers and criminals are constantly looking for such vulnerabilities. Companies that create software fix vulnerabilities through security patches released in updates. Therefore, it is important to install updates as soon as they become available.</p>
<p>Whichever device you use, make sure you are using the latest version of the operating system. It is a good idea to set the operating system and antivirus software to update automatically. Update the rest of software on your devices often and on a regular basis.</p>
<p>If there have been no updates to the operating system on your mobile phone offered within the last six months, it is highly likely that it is an older model that the manufacturer no longer supports. In this case, consider replacing the phone with a newer model that gets critical security updates.</p>
<h2>3. Use a non-admin account</h2>
<p>Malware can be particularly devastating for your device and data on it when you are logged in an administrator account. It is a good idea to create a user account with limited privileges on your computer and use it for regular daily tasks. When you are signed in to an account with restricted privileges, it is much harder for malware to find a way into your device and make system-wide changes.</p>
<h2>4. Know what you install</h2>
<p>A lot of malware is bundled with shady software or built into pirated versions of legitimate software. One of the surest ways to infect your computer with malware is to install pirated (unlicensed) software on it. If you really need a particular piece of software but cannot afford it, keep in mind that there are free alternatives to almost all major software products. These alternatives may offer more limited functionality but they will get the job done without making malware a constant feature of your online experience. When you have a chance, always choose open-source software over proprietary commercial products.</p>
<p>Download apps only through official app stores. When you install something for the first time and are not familiar with the app, make sure you read reviews to find out if other users have found the software trustworthy.</p>
<p>Make it a habit to revisit all apps installed on your devices on a regular basis. Delete the apps that you no longer use or trust.</p>
<h2>5. Beware of attachments</h2>
<p>It is one of the most fundamental digital safety rules that you should never download or open attachments that arrive in emails, social media messages, or mobile texts from people you do not know or do not trust fully. Scammers and criminals are particularly fond of Word, Excel, PowerPoint and PDF files infected with malware. If an email or any other type of message looks strange or suspicious to you, the best way to deal with it is by deleting it right away.</p>
<p>It is also worth remembering that even people you know and trust can have their email accounts compromised. So if you receive an unexpected email with an attachment from them, it is a good idea to check with the person who you think sent you the email before opening it.</p>
<h2>6. Check links before clicking</h2>
<p>You should never click on links sent by people or organizations that you do not know. You should also make it a habit to treat each single link you receive as a potential risk. When you get an alert from a colleague, your bank or the social media service you are using, do not click the link in the email. Hover your mouse over the link to see the full website address. This can help you decide whether or not you want to click that link. Alternatively, you can open a browser window and type of address directly into the URL field to make sure the site is real.</p>
<p>Before clicking on a link that you find even a tiny bit suspicious, scan it with a link scanner such as Norton Safe Web (https://safeweb.norton.com/) that lets you enter the URL of a suspicious link and check it for safety.</p>
<p>Use extra caution when dealing with shortened URL links. Always check the real URL link behind a shortened one. You can use a free online service such as UnshortenIt (https://unshorten.it)/ to “decode” a shortened URL.</p>
<h2>7. Don’t trust pop-up messages</h2>
<p>We have all had this experience: you surf the Internet and suddenly there is a pop-up window telling you that your computer has been infected and recommending that you download some software to protect your device. Do not fall for this. You are smarter than that.</p>
<h2>8. Be careful with removable media</h2>
<p>Malware often travels across different devices via removable media such as USB memory sticks, external hard drives, flash memory cards and so on. Never insert such a device into your computer if you do not know where it came from. When you have to use a removable media device and know where it came from, it is a good idea to use an antivirus program to scan the device before opening it.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-yourself-against-malware/">How to Protect Yourself Against Malware</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Protect Your Personal Information on Social Media</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-your-personal-information-on-social-media/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 04:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles#038;p=401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you are like most other people who spend a lot of time on social media, it is highly likely that you are sharing a lot of your personal information online. The details that our various social media accounts reveal often include our full names, schools we go to, organizations we work for, our family [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-your-personal-information-on-social-media/">How to Protect Your Personal Information on Social Media</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you are like most other people who spend a lot of time on social media, it is highly likely that you are sharing a lot of your personal information online. The details that our various social media accounts reveal often include our full names, schools we go to, organizations we work for, our family connections and friends, places we live in or visit often, our hobbies and interests, political leanings and musical preferences, and so on.</p>
<p>All of this information can be used against us. Fraudsters can use your personal details to impersonate you and fool your friends or colleagues into sending them money or giving up sensitive information. They can also use information gathered on your social media accounts to guess your security questions on banking or dating sites, steal your online accounts, or harass you.</p>
<p>The good news is that a few quick and easy fixes listed below will help you keep your personal information safe while still enjoying the benefits of making social media connections.</p>
<h2>1. Use strong and unique passwords</h2>
<p>Protect every social media account you have with a password that is impossible to guess or crack. A password is strong when it has at least 12 characters, including upper- and lower-case letters, numbers, and special symbols. Random combinations of these characters make the strongest passwords. Read more about <a title="How to Create Strong Passwords" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-create-strong-passwords/">how to create passwords that are hard to crack</a>.</p>
<p>Make sure to use a unique password for every online account you have. Read more about <a title="Why All of Your Passwords Should Be Unique" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-all-of-your-passwords-should-be-unique/">why it is a really bad idea to use the same or similar password for different accounts</a>. Do not fret over having so many complex and unique passwords &#8211; you can <a title="Why You Should Use a Password Manager" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-you-should-use-a-password-manager/">use a password manager</a> to “remember” and store them safely for you.</p>
<h2>2. Add a second layer of protection</h2>
<p>Unfortunately even the strongest password can be stolen or compromised in some other way. This is why you should use two-factor authentication (2FA) to protect your social media accounts. When enabled, 2FA requires that you use a second way of proving your identity in addition to entering a password.</p>
<p>The safest way to use 2FA is to install an app on your smartphone that will generate temporary numerical codes. To access a social media account, you will need to enter such a code immediately after entering your password. Read more about <a title="Why You Should Use Two-Factor Authentication" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-you-should-use-two-factor-authentication/">how to use two-factor authentication to protect online accounts</a>.</p>
<h2>3. Keep your software up-to-date</h2>
<p>In a world where cybercriminals are increasingly good at exploiting vulnerabilities in the various apps people have on their devices, it is very important to keep your software up-to-date. Make sure that the device you are using to access your social media accounts always has the latest version of the operating system running. Whether you are using a computer or a mobile device, make sure that you have an antivirus running and that it is set to update automatically.</p>
<p>If you access social media sites in a web browser, make sure that the browser is up-to-date. If you use dedicated social media apps on a mobile device, update them often.</p>
<h2>4. Know the people you friend</h2>
<p>This is pretty straightforward: the more people you are connected to, the harder it is to control what happens to the personal information you share on social media. Unless you have a good reason to keep your social media accounts open to everyone, consider restricting who can view your posts and photos. Read more about how to do so on <a title="How to Protect Your Privacy on Instagram" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-your-privacy-on-instagram/">Instagram</a> and <a title="How to Protect Your Privacy on Twitter" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-your-privacy-on-twitter/">Twitter</a>.</p>
<p>It is a good idea to regularly revisit the lists of your followers on the various social media services you are using. Consider removing people you no longer trust or communicate with. If a user is asking you for personal information, disturbs you or does something else in a way that makes you suspicious of their motives, consider blocking and reporting such profiles.</p>
<h2>5. Manage your privacy settings</h2>
<p>Social media services are designed to make your posts and photos accessible to as many users all over the world as possible. Fortunately, these services also allow you to adjust the default privacy settings so you can control exactly how much others can see. For instance, most social media sites allow you to limit who can view your profile, block specific users, share photos only with specific people and so on. Make sure you learn how to use these settings and manage them to maximize your privacy. Read more about how to manage privacy settings on <a title="How to Protect Your Privacy on Instagram" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-your-privacy-on-instagram/">Instagram</a> and <a title="How to Protect Your Privacy on Twitter" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-your-privacy-on-twitter/">Twitter</a>.</p>
<h2>6. Keep your personal information off social media</h2>
<p>Social media sites give you the option of adding a lot of personal details to help others find you. Where did you go to school? Are you married? Who else from your family has an account with us? These details give social media sites a very intimate portrait of your life and provide a real treasure trove for ill-meaning people.</p>
<p>Try to limit the amount of personal information you post, including biographical details, family connections, and photos. Do not ever share photos of your IDs, concert tickets or boarding passes. Think ahead and remember that once you post something, it is almost impossible to take it back or know who exactly has access to this information.</p>
<h2>7. Don’t share your location</h2>
<p>One way social media users often make themselves an easy target for ill-meaning people is by telling everyone where they are and where they often go. We do it by using a check-in feature on social media apps, posting photos that show where we are or writing about a wonderful experience we are having somewhere.</p>
<p>If you care about privacy and personal safety, it is a good idea not to share your location with others. Turn off your gadget’s location sharing and adjust privacy settings on the social media services to stop them from tracking your location. Do not use social media check-in features and do not post photos that show where you are, at least until you leave the place.</p>
<h2>8. Don’t use your social profiles to log into other websites</h2>
<p>It may be tempting to use the “Log in with Facebook” option when creating a new online account. Yet by doing so, you are trusting the third party site you are logging into with your Facebook credentials. Even in pure statistical terms, this increases the odds that your account will be compromised. You are also providing Facebook with access to even more of your personal data. So, never log into other websites with your social media accounts.</p>
<h2>9. Don’t give other apps access to your accounts</h2>
<p>Most users are completely unaware of how many apps or websites they have given permission to link to their social media accounts. Every time you click on a quiz someone shares on Facebook or tap “Click to see which celebrity you look like,” you are granting an additional app or service access to your account. These apps can potentially see who you are friends with, access your profile pictures, birthday and address details, and so on.</p>
<p>Revisit the list of apps and services that have access to your social media accounts on a regular basis. Remove everything that is outdated, suspicious or no longer being used.</p>
<h2>10. Know how to handle public and shared devices</h2>
<p>Logging into social media accounts on public or shared devices always puts your personal information at risk. While you can minimize some of these risks, you cannot really eliminate them. When you use a public device at a library, school or airport to check your social media profiles, make sure you always log out after you are finished and, when possible, end your session or reboot the device.</p>
<p>Try not to log into your social media accounts on shared computers at internet cafes. Always assume that such computers have keyloggers or other types of spyware installed on them. If you absolutely have to check a social media account at an Internet cafe, make sure you have two-factor authentication enabled on your account and change your password from a different computer soon after you access the account.</p>
<h2>11. Watch out for links</h2>
<p>It is one of the foundational digital safety rules that you should never click on links from people you don&#8217;t know or don’t fully trust. This applies to links on social media, too. Such links can be sent to you via private messages or posted in comments under a photo or a status update. If you don’t know exactly where a link will take you, don’t click on it.</p>
<p>Hovering over a link will give you more information about where it leads if clicked &#8211; but this option is not available on mobile devices.</p>
<h2>12. Close unused accounts</h2>
<p>As newer and trendier social media platforms replace the outdated ones, it is important to keep track of all the accounts you have opened and delete the ones you are no longer using. It is easier for hackers to compromise your abandoned or forgotten accounts without you noticing it.</p>
<p>A compromised account and all the information in it can then be leveraged to hack into other accounts or impersonate you. In addition to closing the accounts you are no longer using, ask the social media service, where possible, to delete all of the information they have on you. One of the advantages of using a password manager is that it makes it easier to keep track of all the accounts you open.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-your-personal-information-on-social-media/">How to Protect Your Personal Information on Social Media</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Protect Your Privacy on Instagram</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-your-privacy-on-instagram/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 04:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles#038;p=400</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By its very design, your Instagram profile reveals more personal details about you than any other social networking site. Unless you change the default privacy settings on Instagram, the service tries to make everything you share visible to as many people as possible. This has even caused some users to delete their Instagram accounts. The [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-your-privacy-on-instagram/">How to Protect Your Privacy on Instagram</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By its very design, your Instagram profile reveals more personal details about you than any other social networking site. Unless you change the default privacy settings on Instagram, the service tries to make everything you share visible to as many people as possible. This has even caused some users to delete their Instagram accounts. The good news is that a few quick and easy fixes shown below will help you gain control of your privacy on Instagram.</p>
<p>This guide will walk you through Instagram privacy settings accessed through a mobile app. Things may look a bit different if you access these settings by opening Instagram in a web browser.</p>
<h2>1. Set your account to private</h2>
<p>Unless you have a serious reason to keep your Instagram profile public, it is a good idea to regain control over who can see the photos and stories you post on the app. By default, every Instagram account is set to public. This means that everything you have ever shared on the service can be seen by anyone anywhere in the world &#8211; even by people who do not have an Instagram account.</p>
<p>You can control who gets to see your photos and stories by setting your account to private. When you do so, people who are not already among your followers can request to follow you. Before they can see your photos or stories, you have to confirm their request.</p>
<p>To set your Instagram account to private, tap on your profile picture in the bottom right of the screen to go to your profile. Here tap the three-lined menu in the top right and select <strong>Settings</strong>. Navigate to <strong>Privacy</strong> and enable <strong>Private Account</strong>. Confirm that you want to switch to a private account.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-438" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings.jpg" alt="Instagram Settings." width="1600" height="1599" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings-1200x1199.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-434" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_private_account.jpg" alt="Switch for enabling Private Account on Instagram." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_private_account.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_private_account-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_private_account-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_private_account-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_private_account-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_private_account-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_private_account-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-442" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instragram_private_account_enabled.jpg" alt="Confirmation to switch to a Private Account on Instagram." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instragram_private_account_enabled.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instragram_private_account_enabled-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instragram_private_account_enabled-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instragram_private_account_enabled-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instragram_private_account_enabled-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instragram_private_account_enabled-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instragram_private_account_enabled-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<h2>2. Manage your approved followers</h2>
<p>When you set your account to private, all the people who are already following you will continue seeing everything you post. So it is a good idea to review who follows you and remove people you do not know or do not want to see your photos or stories.</p>
<p>To see everyone who follows you, tap on your profile picture in the bottom right of the screen to go to your profile. Here tap <strong>Followers</strong> next to your profile photo and review everyone who is allowed to see what you share. To remove a user from the list of your followers, tap <strong>Remove</strong> next to their profile picture and name.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-435" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_remove_followers.jpg" alt="Removing followers on Instagram with Remove button in the followers list." width="1600" height="1599" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_remove_followers.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_remove_followers-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_remove_followers-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_remove_followers-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_remove_followers-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_remove_followers-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_remove_followers-1200x1199.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<h2>3. Block people from seeing your feed</h2>
<p>If you want to keep your account public, you can still block individual users from seeing your posts and stories. This comes particularly handy if you ever have to deal with trolls or people leaving offensive or inappropriate comments.</p>
<p>To block someone, go to their profile. On their profile page, tap the three-dotten menu in the top right. Tap <strong>Block</strong> in the drop-down menu.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-425" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_block_user.jpg" alt="Block a user on Instagram." width="1600" height="1599" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_block_user.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_block_user-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_block_user-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_block_user-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_block_user-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_block_user-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_block_user-1200x1199.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<h2>4. Control who sees and shares your stories</h2>
<p>You can also control who gets to see your stories and whether they can reply to or share them. Instagram allows you to hide stories from individual followers or make your stories visible only to a select group of followers.</p>
<p>To limit who sees your stories, tap on your profile picture in the bottom right of the screen to go to your profile. Here tap the three-lined menu in the top right and select <strong>Settings</strong>. Tap <strong>Privacy</strong> and then select <strong>Story</strong>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-433" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_story.jpg" alt="Story under Privacy settings on Instagram." width="1600" height="1599" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_story.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_story-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_story-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_story-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_story-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_story-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_story-1200x1199.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Under <strong>Viewing</strong>, you can block individual people from seeing your stories by tapping <strong>Hide Story From</strong>. You can also restrict who is allowed to view your stories by tapping <strong>Close Friends</strong> and specifying who you want to be in this circle.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-439" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_close_friends.jpg" alt="Choose people to hide Instagram stories and sharing Instagram stories with only Close Friends." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_close_friends.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_close_friends-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_close_friends-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_close_friends-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_close_friends-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_close_friends-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_close_friends-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>The <strong>Story</strong> menu also allows you to limit who can reply to your stories. Under <strong>Allow Message Replies</strong>, you can extend this privilege to anyone who sees your stories, restrict it to people following you, or disable story replies altogether.</p>
<p>Here you can also control whether you want to allow other people to add photos you post to their stories and to share your stories in messages they send to other people. To adjust these controls, navigate to <strong>Sharing</strong>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-440" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_sharing_options.jpg" alt="Allowing message replies to your Instagram stories and allowing people to share your Instagram story in their stories or messages." width="1600" height="1599" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_sharing_options.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_sharing_options-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_sharing_options-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_sharing_options-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_sharing_options-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_sharing_options-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_story_sharing_options-1200x1199.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<h2>5. Turn off activity status</h2>
<p>Your activity status tells other Instagram users when you are online. You can turn this feature off if you do not want other users to know when you are scrolling through the app. Note that if you disable activity status, you will also not be able to see when the people you follow are online.</p>
<p>To turn off your activity status on Instagram, tap on your profile picture in the bottom right of the screen to go to your profile. Here tap the three-lined menu in the top right and select <strong>Settings</strong>. Navigate to <strong>Privacy</strong>, scroll down and tap <strong>Activity Status</strong>. Disable <strong>Show Activity Status</strong>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-438" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings.jpg" alt="Instagram Settings." width="1600" height="1599" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings-1200x1199.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-430" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_activity_status.jpg" alt="Activity Status under Privacy settings on Instagram." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_activity_status.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_activity_status-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_activity_status-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_activity_status-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_activity_status-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_activity_status-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_activity_status-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-423" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_activity_switch.jpg" alt="Show activity status switch on Instagram." width="1600" height="1599" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_activity_switch.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_activity_switch-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_activity_switch-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_activity_switch-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_activity_switch-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_activity_switch-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_activity_switch-1200x1199.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<h2>6. Control comments on your posts</h2>
<p>Although comments people write under your Instagram posts do not often compromise your privacy, they can sometimes reveal personal details that you would not want others to see. Comment controls also allow you to make your Instagram experience much more enjoyable by weeding out offensive or inappropriate messages.</p>
<p>To limit who is allowed to comment on your posts, tap on your profile picture in the bottom right of the screen to go to your profile. Here tap the three-lined menu in the top right and select <strong>Settings</strong>. Navigate to <strong>Privacy</strong> and select <strong>Comments</strong>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-431" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_comments.jpg" alt="Comments under Privacy settings on Instagram." width="1400" height="1400" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_comments.jpg 1400w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_comments-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_comments-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_comments-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_comments-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_comments-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1400px) 100vw, 1400px" /></p>
<p>Here, under <strong>Controls</strong>, you can specify who is allowed to comment on your posts or block individual followers from being able to post any comments in your feed.</p>
<p>You can also tell Instagram to hide all offensive or inappropriate comments from your posts and stories by navigating to <strong>Filters</strong> and enabling the <strong>Hide Offensive Comments</strong> function.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-428" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_offensive_comments.jpg" alt="Hiding offensive comments on Instagram." width="1400" height="1400" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_offensive_comments.jpg 1400w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_offensive_comments-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_offensive_comments-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_offensive_comments-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_offensive_comments-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_offensive_comments-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1400px) 100vw, 1400px" /></p>
<h2>7. Disable tagging</h2>
<p>Your privacy on Instagram can also be compromised by other people if they tag you in images they upload. So it is a good idea to limit who is allowed to tag you in their photos on Instagram and to review all tagged photos before they are posted to your profile.</p>
<p>To do this, tap on your profile picture in the bottom right of the screen to go to your profile. Here tap the three-lined menu in the top right and select <strong>Settings</strong>. Tap <strong>Privacy</strong> and then tap <strong>Posts</strong>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-432" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_posts.jpg" alt="Posts under Privacy settings on Instagram." width="1600" height="1599" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_posts.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_posts-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_posts-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_posts-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_posts-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_posts-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_privacy_posts-1200x1199.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Here, under <strong>Allow Tags From</strong>, choose who can tag you in their photos. Then scroll down, tap <strong>Manually Approve Tags</strong> and turn on this function.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-441" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_tags.jpg" alt="Allowing Tags From Instagram options and enabling manually approving tags." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_tags.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_tags-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_tags-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_tags-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_tags-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_tags-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_tags-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-424" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_approve_tags_manually.jpg" alt="Turn on manually approving tags on Instagram." width="1600" height="1599" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_approve_tags_manually.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_approve_tags_manually-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_approve_tags_manually-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_approve_tags_manually-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_approve_tags_manually-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_approve_tags_manually-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_approve_tags_manually-1200x1199.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<h2>8. Stop saving your posts and stories</h2>
<p>Instagram helps users preserve all photos and videos they post by saving them. This is something you may actually not want Instagram to do, especially when it comes to disappearing stories.</p>
<p>To stop Instagram from saving the photos you share to your device, tap on your profile picture in the bottom right of the screen to go to your profile. Here tap the three-lined menu in the top right and select <strong>Settings</strong>. Tap <strong>Account</strong> and, then, tap <strong>Original Photos</strong>. Disable the option <strong>Save Original Photos</strong>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-436" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_account.jpg" alt="Accessing Account in the Instagram Settings." width="1600" height="1599" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_account.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_account-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_account-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_account-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_account-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_account-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_account-1200x1199.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-429" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_original_photos_switch.jpg" alt="Switch for saving original photos on Instagram." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_original_photos_switch.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_original_photos_switch-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_original_photos_switch-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_original_photos_switch-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_original_photos_switch-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_original_photos_switch-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_original_photos_switch-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>To stop Instagram from saving your stories and live videos, tap on your profile picture in the bottom right of the screen to go to your profile. Here tap the three-lined menu in the top right and select <strong>Settings</strong>. Tap <strong>Privacy</strong> and, then, tap <strong>Story</strong>. Now disable all three options (<strong>Save Story to Camera Roll</strong>, <strong>Save Story to Archive</strong>, and <strong>Save Live to Archive</strong>).</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-437" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_privacy.jpg" alt="Accessing Privacy in the Instagram Settings." width="1600" height="1599" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_privacy.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_privacy-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_privacy-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_privacy-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_privacy-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_privacy-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_settings_privacy-1200x1199.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-426" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_camera_roll.jpg" alt="Switch for saving Instagram stories to Camera Roll." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_camera_roll.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_camera_roll-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_camera_roll-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_camera_roll-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_camera_roll-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_camera_roll-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_camera_roll-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-427" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_live_archive.jpg" alt="Switch for saving live video to archive on Instagram." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_live_archive.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_live_archive-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_live_archive-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_live_archive-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_live_archive-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_live_archive-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/instagram_live_archive-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-your-privacy-on-instagram/">How to Protect Your Privacy on Instagram</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Protect Your Privacy on Twitter</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-your-privacy-on-twitter/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 04:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles#038;p=399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Just like all other social media sites, Twitter collects a lot of your personal information and reveals many of your personal details to other users. This has even caused some users to delete their Instagram accounts. The good news is that a few quick and easy fixes shown below will help you gain control of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-your-privacy-on-twitter/">How to Protect Your Privacy on Twitter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just like all other social media sites, Twitter collects a lot of your personal information and reveals many of your personal details to other users. This has even caused some users to delete their Instagram accounts. The good news is that a few quick and easy fixes shown below will help you gain control of your privacy on Twitter.</p>
<p>This guide will walk you through Twitter privacy settings accessed in a web browser. Things may look a bit different if you access these settings on an app on your mobile device.</p>
<h2>1. Make your account private</h2>
<p>Unless you want to keep your Twitter profile public, it is a good idea to regain control over who can see your posts. By default, every Twitter account is set to public. This means that everything you have ever posted on the service can be seen by anyone anywhere in the world &#8211; even by people who do not have a Twitter account.</p>
<p>You can control who gets to see your Tweets by making your account private. When you do so, people who are not already among your followers can request to follow you. Before they can see your Tweets, you have to confirm their request.</p>
<p>To set your Twitter account to private, open Twitter’s settings and head to <strong>Privacy and Safety</strong>. Select <strong>Audience and tagging</strong> and set the check mark next to <strong>Protect your tweets</strong>. Confirm the selection by clicking <strong>Protect</strong>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-403" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_more_options.jpg" alt="Screenshot of More options button on Twitter profile page." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_more_options.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_more_options-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_more_options-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_more_options-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_more_options-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_more_options-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-404" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_settings_privacy.jpg" alt="Settings and Privacy link on Twitter profile page." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_settings_privacy.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_settings_privacy-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_settings_privacy-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_settings_privacy-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_settings_privacy-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_settings_privacy-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-405" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_privacy_safety.jpg" alt="Privacy and Safety option in Twitter Settings." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_privacy_safety.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_privacy_safety-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_privacy_safety-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_privacy_safety-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_privacy_safety-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_privacy_safety-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-406" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_audience_tagging.jpg" alt="Audience and Tagging option under Privacy and safety on Twitter settings." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_audience_tagging.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_audience_tagging-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_audience_tagging-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_audience_tagging-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_audience_tagging-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_audience_tagging-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-407" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_protect_tweets.jpg" alt="Protect your tweets checkbox on Twitter Audience and tagging settings." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_protect_tweets.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_protect_tweets-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_protect_tweets-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_protect_tweets-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_protect_tweets-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_protect_tweets-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-408" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_confirm_protection.jpg" alt="Confirmation message after checking Protect your tweets checkbox on Twitter Audience and tagging settings." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_confirm_protection.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_confirm_protection-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_confirm_protection-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_confirm_protection-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_confirm_protection-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_confirm_protection-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-409" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_protect_tweets_checked.jpg" alt="Protect your tweets checkbox checked on Twitter Audience and tagging settings page." width="1600" height="1352" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_protect_tweets_checked.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_protect_tweets_checked-300x254.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_protect_tweets_checked-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_protect_tweets_checked-768x649.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_protect_tweets_checked-1536x1298.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_protect_tweets_checked-1200x1014.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>It is worth keeping in mind that even after you set your Twitter account to private, all your previously published Tweets will remain public.</p>
<h2>2. Stop Twitter from showing your location</h2>
<p>Twitter knows your approximate location by tracking your IP address. In addition to using this information to send you targeted ads and recommendations, Twitter lets you tell other people on the service where you are tweeting from by adding geotags to your posts.</p>
<p>To turn off geotagging, open Twitter’s settings and navigate to <strong>Privacy and Safety</strong>. Scroll down and tap <strong>Location information</strong> under <strong>Data sharing and off-Twitter activity</strong>. Tap <strong>Add location information to your tweets</strong> and disable this option.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-405" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_privacy_safety.jpg" alt="Privacy and Safety option in Twitter Settings." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_privacy_safety.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_privacy_safety-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_privacy_safety-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_privacy_safety-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_privacy_safety-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_privacy_safety-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-417" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_information.jpg" alt="Location information option in Twitter settings." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_information.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_information-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_information-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_information-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_information-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_information-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-418" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_tweets.jpg" alt="Twitter option to add location information to your Tweets." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_tweets.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_tweets-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_tweets-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_tweets-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_tweets-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_tweets-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-416" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_checkbox.jpg" alt="Checkbox to add location information to Tweets in Twitter settings." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_checkbox.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_checkbox-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_checkbox-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_checkbox-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_checkbox-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_location_checkbox-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Here you can also remove geotags from previously published tweets by clicking <strong>Remove all location information attached to your Tweets</strong> and confirming the selection.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-420" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_remove_all_location.jpg" alt="Twitter option to remove all location information attached to your Tweets." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_remove_all_location.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_remove_all_location-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_remove_all_location-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_remove_all_location-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_remove_all_location-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_remove_all_location-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<h2>3. Turn off data collection</h2>
<p>Unless you change the default settings, Twitter tracks all of your online activity outside of the social networking service to customize targeted ads and recommendations. Twitter gets some of this information from its partners and shares your details with its commercial partners.</p>
<p>To stop Twitter from collecting and using your personal information, visit the <a title="Personalization and data" href="https://twitter.com/settings/account/personalization" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Personalization</a> settings page. To go to the page, you have to click on the actual link (<a title="Personalization and data" href="https://twitter.com/settings/account/personalization" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here it is again</a>) as Twitter has recently made it inaccessible through the settings menu when you open the site in a web browser.</p>
<blockquote><p>To access Personalization settings on a Twitter app on an iOS or Android device, tap the icon of your profile photo in the upper-left corner, select <strong>Settings and privacy</strong>, select <strong>Privacy and safety</strong>, and tap <strong>Personalization and data</strong>.</p></blockquote>
<p>Click on the toggle next to <strong>Personalization and data</strong> to switch it off. In the dialogue window that pops up, select <strong>Disable</strong> to confirm the selection.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-419" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_personalization.jpg" alt="Twitter Personalization and data switch." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_personalization.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_personalization-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_personalization-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_personalization-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_personalization-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_personalization-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-415" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_disable_personalization.jpg" alt="Confirmation to disable personalization and data in Twitter settings." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_disable_personalization.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_disable_personalization-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_disable_personalization-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_disable_personalization-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_disable_personalization-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_disable_personalization-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<h2>4. Disable access for third-party apps</h2>
<p>You may have linked other apps or services to your Twitter account. In some cases, apps and websites linked to your account can obtain access to your data and even follow or unfollow accounts on your behalf. If you care about your privacy, you may want to review which third-party applications and services can access your account and disable their access.</p>
<p>To do so, open Twitter settings and click on Security and account access. Select <strong>Apps and sessions</strong> and tap <strong>Connected apps</strong>. Review the list of apps and services that have access to your profile. To block an app from accessing your account, click on it and select <strong>Revoke app permissions</strong>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-422" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_security_account.jpg" alt="Twitter Security and account access settings." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_security_account.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_security_account-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_security_account-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_security_account-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_security_account-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_security_account-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-411" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_apps_sessions.jpg" alt="Apps and sessions option in Twitter settings." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_apps_sessions.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_apps_sessions-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_apps_sessions-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_apps_sessions-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_apps_sessions-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_apps_sessions-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-413" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_connected_apps.jpg" alt="Connected apps option in Twitter settings." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_connected_apps.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_connected_apps-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_connected_apps-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_connected_apps-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_connected_apps-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_connected_apps-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-414" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_connected_namecheap.jpg" alt="List of connected apps to the Twitter account." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_connected_namecheap.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_connected_namecheap-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_connected_namecheap-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_connected_namecheap-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_connected_namecheap-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_connected_namecheap-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-421" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_revoke_app.jpg" alt="Twitter option to revoke app permissions." width="1600" height="1352" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_revoke_app.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_revoke_app-300x254.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_revoke_app-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_revoke_app-768x649.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_revoke_app-1536x1298.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_revoke_app-1200x1014.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<h2>5. Block specific people</h2>
<p>If you want to keep your Twitter account public, you can still block specific people from seeing and replying to your tweets. The blocked users will not be able to view your profile or send you direct messages.</p>
<p>To block someone, go to their profile and click the <strong>three-dot icon</strong> to the left of <strong>Follow</strong> or <strong>Following</strong> and select <strong>Block @username</strong>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-410" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_account_profile_options.jpg" alt="Three dots to access more information on a Twitter account." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_account_profile_options.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_account_profile_options-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_account_profile_options-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_account_profile_options-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_account_profile_options-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_account_profile_options-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-412" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_block_someone.jpg" alt="Blocking an account on Twitter." width="1600" height="1351" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_block_someone.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_block_someone-300x253.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_block_someone-1024x865.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_block_someone-768x648.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_block_someone-1536x1297.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/twitter_block_someone-1200x1013.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-protect-your-privacy-on-twitter/">How to Protect Your Privacy on Twitter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Renovate Your Social Media Profile</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/renovate-your-social-media-profile-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 04:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles#038;p=398</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/renovate-your-social-media-profile-2/">Renovate Your Social Media Profile</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/renovate-your-social-media-profile-2/">Renovate Your Social Media Profile</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
