<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Passwords Archives - CyberSTAR</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-categories/passwords/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cyber-star.org/</link>
	<description>CyberSTAR</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 02:54:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How to Create Strong Passwords</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-create-strong-passwords/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-create-strong-passwords</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 19:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles&#038;p=166</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Our personal and professional lives increasingly revolve around online accounts. Email, social media, file sharing, messaging, video watching, banking, shopping, backing up data &#8211; all of these services require users to have accounts. So you probably have dozens of various accounts to remember and keep safe. Passwords are your first line of defense against anyone [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-create-strong-passwords/">How to Create Strong Passwords</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our personal and professional lives increasingly revolve around online accounts. Email, social media, file sharing, messaging, video watching, banking, shopping, backing up data &#8211; all of these services require users to have accounts. So you probably have dozens of various accounts to remember and keep safe.</p>
<p>Passwords are your first line of defense against anyone who would like to steal these accounts, spy on you, or use your data or documents accessed through these accounts for criminal purposes.</p>
<h3>You need strong passwords</h3>
<p>Not all passwords are equally good at protecting accounts. Hundreds of millions of users around the world still use passwords that are very easy to guess or hack. Gone are the days when passwords were cracked by supersmart hackers with years of experience and unique skills and tools. Today most passwords are hacked through widely available software that tries different combinations of known words and characters until it finds the one that works. This method of cracking a password is known as <em>brute force</em> attack.</p>
<p>So in order to protect your accounts and information in them, you need to protect them with strong passwords, that is, passwords that are very difficult to crack. In practice, this means using passwords that are so complex that cracking them with brute force tools will require too much time for anyone to even consider.</p>
<h3>Create a password that is hard to crack</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Make it long</strong><br />
This is the most critical factor. Use at least 12 characters, more if possible.</li>
<li><strong>Mix characters</strong><br />
The more you mix up upper-case and lower-case letters, numbers and symbols, the harder your password is to crack. Passwords made up of random characters are much stronger than those containing words. So, the password iLoVeYOu56&amp;# is stronger than iloveyou9!, but a much more secure option would be iL3*Ov50&amp;0Ey6824(2uO.</li>
<li><strong>Don’t use memorable keyboard paths or obvious words</strong><br />
Passwords like qwerty, 12345678, password123 and myemailpass are easiest to crack.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid common substitutions</strong><br />
Although character substitutions make passwords stronger, avoid the most common character substitutions. D00RB3LL is a slight improvement over DOORBELL but it is still very easy to crack. Include random characters instead.</li>
<li><strong>Don’t use personal information</strong><br />
If you are at risk of being specifically targeted for a password hack, the hacker will put everything they know about you in their guess attempts. This may include your dog’s name, the city you were born in, the sports team you are rooting for, your child’s name, your date of birth and so on.</li>
<li><strong>Don’t reuse passwords</strong><br />
Ideally all of your accounts and devices should have unique passwords. If someone steals or cracks a password to one of your accounts, they will try to hack into all other accounts you have by trying the stolen password and its modifications.</li>
</ul>
<p>At this point, you might feel that having really strong passwords for each of your accounts is a bit too much. How will you remember all these passwords? Well, you only need to remember a single strong password. A <a title="Why You Should Use a Password Manager" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-you-should-use-a-password-manager/">password manager</a> will do the rest for you.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-create-strong-passwords/">How to Create Strong Passwords</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Passwords That Look Strong But Aren’t</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/passwords-that-look-strong-but-arent/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=passwords-that-look-strong-but-arent</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 19:40:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles&#038;p=170</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Almost all online services now require users to create complex passwords by adding upper-case letters, numbers and special characters. Fortifying a password to satisfy Gmail or Facebook requirements gives users a renewed sense of security. But this sense is often false. Creating a password that meets minimum complexity requirements is not the same as creating [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/passwords-that-look-strong-but-arent/">Passwords That Look Strong But Aren’t</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Almost all online services now require users to create complex passwords by adding upper-case letters, numbers and special characters. Fortifying a password to satisfy Gmail or Facebook requirements gives users a renewed sense of security. But this sense is often false. Creating a password that meets minimum complexity requirements is not the same as <a title="How to Create Strong Passwords" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-create-strong-passwords/">creating a genuinely strong and secure password</a>.</p>
<p>The problem is that most users follow the same pattern when they beef up their passwords to meet an online service’s requirements. Hackers know these patterns very well and use the knowledge to crack passwords. So, a lot of passwords that look strong are actually not very difficult to crack.</p>
<p>Below is a list of the most common mistakes users make when trying to strengthen their passwords. Do not make these mistakes.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Adding a number at the end<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Many users mistakenly believe that they make their passwords strong by adding a number at the end. Most often it is a single-digit number, commonly <em>1</em>. Hackers know this, and when they try to crack a password, they assume that it follows this common pattern.</p>
<p><span style="color: #c01d24;">To create a genuinely strong password, add several random numbers in a random order.</span></li>
<li><strong>Capitalizing the first letter<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Users also tend to create passwords with a single upper-case letter, typically by capitalizing the first letter in a password. Again, this is something hackers know and use to crack passwords.</p>
<p><span style="color: #c01d24;"><span style="color: #c01d24;">To create a strong password, use random combinations of upper-case and lower-case letters.</span></span></li>
<li><strong>Adding a special character at the end<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Another common mistake users make is adding a single special character at the end of a password. Most often the character they go for is <em>!</em>. Adding a special character in this way does not really make a password much more difficult to crack.</p>
<p><span style="color: #c01d24;"><br />
To create a genuinely strong password, add several randomly selected special characters in a random order.</span></li>
<li><strong>Using common words or character sequences<br />
</strong></p>
<p>You would be surprised to know how many users have the same common words (e.g. <em>password, welcome, football, superman</em>, etc.) or computer keyboard sequences (e.g. <em>qwerty, asdfgh, qazwsx,</em> etc.) in their passwords. Hackers use all these words to crack passwords through brute force attacks. These attacks involve the use of software that tries different combinations of common words and characters until it finds the one that works. Other common words used in millions of passwords include first names, the names of cities, countries, and sports teams.</p>
<p><span style="color: #c01d24;">To create a password that is really difficult to crack, use random combinations of upper-case and lower-case letters, numbers, and special characters, rather than common words or computer keyboard and smartphone patterns.</span></li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/passwords-that-look-strong-but-arent/">Passwords That Look Strong But Aren’t</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why All of Your Passwords Should Be Unique</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-all-of-your-passwords-should-be-unique/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=why-all-of-your-passwords-should-be-unique</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 19:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles&#038;p=171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>All of your accounts should have unique passwords that you have never used before. Even if you have the strongest password in the world, you are putting yourself at huge risk if you use it across multiple accounts. What happens when you reuse your passwords Let’s say you use the same password for your personal [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-all-of-your-passwords-should-be-unique/">Why All of Your Passwords Should Be Unique</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>All of your accounts should have unique passwords that you have never used before. Even if you have the <a title="How to Create Strong Passwords" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-create-strong-passwords/">strongest password</a> in the world, you are putting yourself at huge risk if you use it across multiple accounts.</p>
<h3>What happens when you reuse your passwords</h3>
<p>Let’s say you use the same password for your personal email, Facebook, and Instagram. If your email provider experiences a security breach (which happens much more often that we realize) and your user credentials are stolen, attackers will try using the stolen password and its slightly changed versions to log on to other sites as well. As a result, all of your accounts using the same password will be compromised.</p>
<p>Reusing passwords is also a bad idea because, just like millions of other users across the world, you probably have a handful of accounts which you created at some point in the past and which have since been out there forgotten or used rarely. It is very likely that at least some of these accounts have been compromised. If an attacker has your email address which is linked to some of these accounts, it is easy to find all compromised accounts using this email address. It is also easy to get leaked passwords to all such accounts. So, if you reuse the same password or slightly changed versions of a single password across multiple accounts, an attacker can compromise all of these accounts by finding a single forgotten account of yours. This is called <em>password stuffing</em>.</p>
<ul>
<li>If you want to check if your email address(es) is linked to any accounts that have been leaked or compromised, you can use <a title="have i been pwned?" href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this service</a>. Simply type the email address in the search field and click “pwned?”.</li>
<li>If the email address has appeared in any account breaches, you will get a list of all the online services where your account credentials have been compromised in any way. Log in to each of these accounts and change your passwords as soon as possible. Also consider protecting your important accounts with <a title="Why You Should Use Two-Factor Authentication" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-you-should-use-two-factor-authentication/">two-factor authentication</a>. Remember, your passwords should be strong and unique. If you no longer use any of these accounts, consider deleting them.</li>
</ul>
<p>At this point, you might feel that having unique passwords for each and every account &#8211; and making sure that these passwords are genuinely strong &#8211; is a bit too much. How will you remember all these passwords? Well, you only need to remember a single strong password. A <a title="Why You Should Use a Password Manager" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-you-should-use-a-password-manager/">password manager</a> will do the rest for you.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-all-of-your-passwords-should-be-unique/">Why All of Your Passwords Should Be Unique</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why You Should Use a Password Manager</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-you-should-use-a-password-manager/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=why-you-should-use-a-password-manager</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 19:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles&#038;p=167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Passwords are your first line of defense against anyone who would like to steal your online accounts or information in these accounts. To protect your accounts, you should use strong passwords that normally include long and random combinations of characters. Such passwords are nearly impossible to remember. Moreover, you should have a genuinely unique password [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-you-should-use-a-password-manager/">Why You Should Use a Password Manager</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Passwords are your first line of defense against anyone who would like to steal your online accounts or information in these accounts. To protect your accounts, you should use <a title="How to Create Strong Passwords" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-create-strong-passwords/">strong passwords</a> that normally include long and random combinations of characters. Such passwords are nearly impossible to remember. Moreover, you should have a genuinely <a title="Why All of Your Passwords Should Be Unique" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-all-of-your-passwords-should-be-unique/">unique password</a> for each of your accounts.</p>
<p>So, how do you remember and keep track of all these passwords? The solution is a password manager.</p>
<p>Think of a password manager as a safe, where you keep dozens or even hundreds of keys (passwords) to all of your accounts. It makes your life easier as you need to remember only one password &#8211; to log into the password manager where all of your other passwords are stored securely.</p>
<h3>What a password manager does</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Remembers your credentials</strong><br />
You probably have dozens or even hundreds of different online accounts. Writing down or typing the credentials for all these accounts (user names, email addresses and passwords) to keep them on a piece of paper or a document on a computer is a very bad idea. Password manager takes the hassle out of keeping track of all these accounts. It remembers all of your passwords and other credentials for you.</li>
<li><strong>Stores them safely</strong><br />
Storing all your passwords in a password manager is much safer than writing them down or typing to keep in a document on a device. Nobody can open your password manager if you protect it with a very strong password. As an additional precaution, you should <a title="Why You Should Use Two-Factor Authentication" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-you-should-use-two-factor-authentication/">use two-factor authentication</a> to secure your password manager.</li>
<li><strong>Creates strong, unique passwords</strong><br />
Password manager also takes the hassle out of creating strong passwords and ensuring that each password is unique to each individual account. Password manager creates passwords for you and allows you to control the length and complexity of your passwords.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Which password manager you should use</h3>
<p>It is up to you to choose a password manager that fits your needs and preferences. There are several reliable and secure options for paying users to choose from. Some antivirus software packages come with built-in password managers. If you choose to pay for a subscription, 1Password, LastPass, Bitwarden Premium, Dashlane, Keeper, and NordPass are safe bets.</p>
<p>Some password managers also offer free plans to users who do not need advanced features. If you decide to go with a free password manager, your safest bet is to choose from open-source options such as BitWarden, KeePass, and KeePassXC.</p>
<p>Password managers fall in one of two general categories depending on where they keep users’ credentials. If you use a local password manager such as KeePassXC, it stores passwords on your own device. Such password managers offer better privacy and security but they require a certain level of technical knowledge and digital hygiene to use them safely.</p>
<p>In contrast, cloud password managers store passwords on cloud servers. This option is safer for those users who have limited technical knowledge and cannot commit to strict digital hygiene which includes automated backups. BitWarden is a free, open-source, cloud-based password manager known for its security and reliability.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-you-should-use-a-password-manager/">Why You Should Use a Password Manager</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why You Should Use Two-Factor Authentication</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-you-should-use-two-factor-authentication/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=why-you-should-use-two-factor-authentication</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 19:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles&#038;p=172</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Passwords are your first line of defence against those who want to steal your accounts or spy on everything that is happening in them. That is why you should protect all of your accounts with really strong and unique passwords. You should also store the passwords safely. Unfortunately, even the strongest password is not enough [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-you-should-use-two-factor-authentication/">Why You Should Use Two-Factor Authentication</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Passwords are your first line of defence against those who want to steal your accounts or spy on everything that is happening in them. That is why you should protect all of your accounts with <a title="How to Create Strong Passwords" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-create-strong-passwords/">really strong</a> and <a title="Why All of Your Passwords Should Be Unique" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-all-of-your-passwords-should-be-unique/">unique</a> passwords. You should also <a title="Why You Should Use a Password Manager" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-you-should-use-a-password-manager/">store the passwords safely</a>.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, even the strongest password is not enough to guarantee that someone will not break into your account. There are several ways in which your password might be compromised. Hackers might steal your credentials directly from the online service provider (which happens much more often than you realize). Someone might install a tiny piece of software on your device that records every key you strike on your keyboard (including all of your passwords). A very dedicated person might crack your password or convince you to reveal it. Finally, someone might use a hidden camera to record your keyboard while you enter a password.</p>
<p>This is why you should use two-factor authentication (2FA) to protect your important online accounts. When enabled, two-factor authentication requires that you use two different ways of proving your identity to access an online account. So, in addition to entering a password (the <em>first</em> factor), you have to provide a second piece of information (the <em>second</em> factor) to verify your identity. Essentially, 2FA provides another layer of protection to your online accounts, keeping them safe even when your passwords are compromised.</p>
<h3>What can serve as the second factor</h3>
<p>Most online accounts allow users to choose from three categories of additional authentication factors:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Something you know:</strong> a piece of information that only you should know such as a PIN code.</li>
<li><strong>Something you have:</strong> a physical object that you should have on you to access online accounts. This can include a security token (a small hardware device) or your smartphone which can be used to receive authentication codes via SMS or special authentication apps.</li>
<li><strong>Something you are:</strong> something unique to your body such as your fingerprint, face or retina.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Which second factor you should choose</h3>
<p>It is very difficult to give general advice on the most suitable 2FA method that would work for every user. Ultimately, you should choose what works best for you based on your own situation, risk assessment and convenience. We will offer several pointers below to help you make an informed choice:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Security questions</strong> make 2FA an easy job as their only requirement is that you remember answers to a number of preset questions. However, it is typically not too hard for a crafty attacker to dig up these answers (e.g. your mother’s maiden name) or trick you into giving away this information.</li>
<li><strong>Security tokens</strong> (U2F keys) provide one of the most secure 2FA methods as long as you keep them physically secure. A major disadvantage of these devices is that they cost money and might require various adapters to use them across devices. Besides, using a security token as the second authentication factor requires you to have the device on you every time you want to access an online account. Thus, there is always a risk of loss or theft.</li>
<li><strong>SMS messages</strong> are very convenient as they arrive instantly on your mobile phone. However, this is one of the least secure 2FA methods as SMS messages can be easily rerouted by a committed individual or intercepted by your mobile service provider.</li>
<li><strong>Authenticator apps</strong> rank among the most secure and convenient 2FA methods. When you link an authenticator app to an online account, it generates temporary passwords or numerical codes that you need to enter immediately after entering your main password to access an online account. These passwords or codes cannot be intercepted as easy as SMS messages can.However, the security of these apps is tied to the security of your mobile device. In order to use them safely, you need to ensure that both your phone and the app you choose are protected by strong passwords. Reliable authenticator apps recommended by experts include Aegis, Authy, Google Authenticator, and LastPass Authenticator. Whichever option you choose, make sure that you save in a secure location one-time backup codes for every account you link to the authenticator app. You will need these codes to access your accounts in case you lose the phone with the app on it.</li>
<li><strong>Biometrics</strong> such as your <strong>fingerprint</strong>, <strong>face</strong> or <strong>voice</strong> are very convenient but not as secure as is often thought. Unfortunately, many of the popular online services do not offer biometrics as a 2FA option. Besides, many users are reluctant to use their biometrics because, unlike passwords, a compromised biometric cannot be changed. Once it is hacked, it is hacked for life. Online services may also sell your biometric data to third parties without your consent.</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-you-should-use-two-factor-authentication/">Why You Should Use Two-Factor Authentication</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secure Passwords: Online Course</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/secure-passwords-online-course/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=secure-passwords-online-course</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 04:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles&#038;p=98</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/secure-passwords-online-course/">Secure Passwords: Online Course</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/secure-passwords-online-course/">Secure Passwords: Online Course</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Make Your Password Stronger</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/make-your-password-stronger/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=make-your-password-stronger</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 04:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles&#038;p=101</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/make-your-password-stronger/">Make Your Password Stronger</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/make-your-password-stronger/">Make Your Password Stronger</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lock Your Digital Door: Care for Your Account Security</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/lock-your-digital-door-care-for-your-account-security/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=lock-your-digital-door-care-for-your-account-security</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 04:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles&#038;p=102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/lock-your-digital-door-care-for-your-account-security/">Lock Your Digital Door: Care for Your Account Security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/lock-your-digital-door-care-for-your-account-security/">Lock Your Digital Door: Care for Your Account Security</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
