<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Conversations &#8211; CyberSTAR</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-categories/conversations/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cyber-star.org/</link>
	<description>CyberSTAR</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 19:24:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Keep Your Digital Conversations Private</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/keep-your-digital-conversations-private/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=keep-your-digital-conversations-private</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 15:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles&#038;p=474</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Digital conversations have become an important part of our daily personal and professional routine. We call friends and family on WhatsApp or Skype, chat with classmates on Facebook messenger, and send emails from personal, school or work accounts. We also text people from our mobile phones and argue with strangers on online discussion boards. All [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/keep-your-digital-conversations-private/">Keep Your Digital Conversations Private</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Digital conversations have become an important part of our daily personal and professional routine. We call friends and family on WhatsApp or Skype, chat with classmates on Facebook messenger, and send emails from personal, school or work accounts. We also text people from our mobile phones and argue with strangers on online discussion boards.</p>
<p>All these conversations travel through complex infrastructure involving multiple routers, servers, and cables. Various people or organizations &#8211; from half-amateur hackers to internet service providers equipped with sophisticated tools &#8211; can tap these conversations at any of these points. Whichever digital communication technology you use, the basic tips listed below can help you keep your online conversations private and secure.</p>
<h3>1. Use encrypted and open-source channels</h3>
<p>While there are many email services and messenger apps on the market, not all of them do an equally good job at keeping your conversations private and secure.</p>
<p>If you want to keep your conversations strictly between you and the people you are communicating with, use apps and services that offer end-to-end encryption. As mentioned above, your digital conversations travel through complex infrastructure and can be intercepted by various actors at numerous points. The only reliable way to secure your conversations is to use services that encrypt (that is, turn into a complex code) everything that leaves your device and do not decrypt it until it reaches the device of the intended recipient. Even if an encrypted email or call is intercepted somewhere between your device and the intended recipient, all that the people who intercept it will see is a string of meaningless characters.</p>
<p>You should also choose open-source apps over proprietary commercial products. Software is open-source when its code is accessible to anyone who wants to see it. It means that independent experts and tech-savvy users can inspect the code that makes up the app, detect and fix vulnerabilities in it, and see whether the app does a good job at securing user data.</p>
<p>ProtonMail offers a free and open-source and end-to-end encrypted email service that protects and secures your email communications. Among free and open-source messenger apps, Wire and Signal are the most secure free end-to-end encrypted options on the market. If you are on Telegram, make sure you use <a title="How to Chat Safely on Telegram" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-chat-safely-on-telegram/">Secret Chats</a> (regular Telegram chats are not end-to-end encrypted).</p>
<h2>2. Secure your devices</h2>
<p>While end-to-end encryption secures your conversations from being tapped on their way between you and the intended recipient, it cannot protect digital communication from being intercepted or monitored on your or the intended recipient’s devices. This can happen, for instance, when you leave your device unattended or lose it without enabling automatic screen lock. This can also happen when your device is infected with malware. A virtually invisible piece of malware on your device can, among other things, record every keyboard stroke and send it to someone.</p>
<p>Always keep software and hardware on your devices up-to-date. Set your devices to lock screens automatically after a brief period of inactivity. Make sure you have antivirus software running on desktops and laptops. <a title="My Devices articles on CyberSTAR" href="https://cyber-star.org/using-the-cyberstar/devices/">Learn more about what you can do to protect your devices</a> (and secure your conversations along the way).</p>
<h2>3. Stop using SMS</h2>
<p>Short messaging service (SMS) that people use to exchange texts on their phones is outdated and insecure. First, SMS messages are not encrypted. They can be intercepted, often without particularly sophisticated tools. Second, these messages carry metadata that identifies the sender and the receiver. Third, it is easy to spoof SMS messages &#8211; that is, to make them appear like they are sent by someone you know. So, you can never know for certain who a particular SMS message is really coming from. Finally, mobile service providers store SMS messages and their metadata for a long time, sometimes forever. This makes it more likely that your conversations will be seen by someone without your knowledge or consent.</p>
<p>If you want to keep the texts you exchange with other people private, use an end-to-end encrypted messaging app from the ones we identified above. When this is not possible, use Android or Apple built-in data-based messaging systems, rather than SMS-based messages.</p>
<h3>Apple device</h3>
<ul>
<li>To make iMessage the default messaging system on an Apple device, go to <strong>Settings &gt; Messages</strong> and turn on <strong>iMessage</strong>. With this setting on, you can send texts, photos, videos, and audio files to other people using iPhones, iPads or Macs over an encrypted connection.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Android device</h3>
<ul>
<li>Most newer Android devices come with Messages, Google’s data-based messaging app. If your Android device does not have the Messages app, <a title="Download Messages on Google Play Store" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.messaging" target="_blank" rel="noopener">download it from the Play Store</a>. To make Messages your default messaging app, go to <strong>Settings &gt; Apps and notifications &gt; Advanced &gt; Default apps &gt; SMS app</strong>. Then, select <strong>Messages</strong> as your default messaging app.</li>
<li>To send encrypted messages through the Messages app, you need to enable chat features. To do so, open the Messages app on your device and tap the three vertical dots in the upper right corner. Select Settings &gt; Chat features. Toggle <strong>Enable chat features</strong> on.</li>
<li>If the Messages app is not available in your country or on your device, use an end-to-end encrypted messaging app from the ones we identified above.</li>
</ul>
<h2>4. Delete old messages</h2>
<p>One way to protect text, photo and video messages on your device from prying eyes is to delete old messages regularly. By doing so, you make sure that other people do not see your messages if your device is lost or stolen (or if someone pressures you into unlocking the device for them). Deleting old messages also saves us space on your device.</p>
<p>It is a good idea to set your device to delete old messages automatically. Unfortunately, this option is not available in Google Messages on Android devices. So, if you use an Android device, you need to delete old messages manually on a regular basis.</p>
<p>To set an iPhone or iPad to delete old messages automatically, go to <strong>Settings &gt; Messages</strong>. Scroll down to the section labelled <strong>MESSAGE HISTORY</strong> and tap <strong>Keep Messages</strong>. Choose <strong>30 Days</strong> to delete all messages older than a month. With this setting on, your device will automatically delete all messages after 30 days. If you want to delete messages before they remain on your device for 30 days, you will need to do so manually.</p>
<p>Keep in mind that deleting messages on your device does not delete them on the devices of the people you sent these messages to.</p>
<h2>5. Use disappearing (timed) messages</h2>
<p>Most messaging apps allow you to send messages that disappear after a certain period or after they are seen by the person you are sending them to. This protects your messages from prying eyes in case your device is compromised or stolen (or if someone pressures you into unlocking the device for them). This also protects your messages from being accessed through the device of the person you are sending them to.</p>
<p>You should strongly consider using disappearing (timed) messages when sending texts, photos or videos. Keep in mind that setting your messages to disappear after a certain period, or as soon as they are read by the person you are sending them to, does not prevent the person from copying these messages and keeping them on their device.</p>
<h2>6. Use strong passwords and 2FA</h2>
<p>Protect every email and messaging-service account you use with a password that is impossible to guess or crack. A password is strong when it has at least 12 characters, including upper- and lower-case letters, numbers, and special symbols. Random combinations of these characters make the strongest passwords. Read more about <a title="How to Create Strong Passwords" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-create-strong-passwords/">how to create passwords that are hard to crack</a>.</p>
<p>Make sure to use a unique password for every account you have. Read more about <a title="Why All of Your Passwords Should Be Unique" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-all-of-your-passwords-should-be-unique/">why it is a really bad idea to use the same or similar password for different accounts</a>. Do not fret over having so many complex and unique passwords &#8211; you can <a title="Why You Should Use a Password Manager" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-you-should-use-a-password-manager/">use a password manager</a> to “remember” and store them safely for you.</p>
<p>Unfortunately even the strongest password can be stolen or compromised in some other way. This is why you should use two-factor authentication (2FA) to protect your email and messaging-service accounts. When enabled, 2FA requires that you use a second way of proving your identity in addition to entering a password.</p>
<p>The safest way to use 2FA is to install an app on your smartphone that will generate temporary numerical codes. To access a social media account, you will need to enter such a code immediately after entering your password. Read more about how to use <a title="Why You Should Use Two-Factor Authentication" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/why-you-should-use-two-factor-authentication/">two-factor authentication to protect online accounts</a>.</p>
<h2>7. Think before sending</h2>
<p>This is really simple: before sending a text, photo or video message, think honestly about whether you may one day regret sending it. Once you hit the “send” button, you often lose control of who has copies of your message. If you have something very private, confidential or sensitive to communicate, the best way to do it is by meeting the person face-to-face.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/keep-your-digital-conversations-private/">Keep Your Digital Conversations Private</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Chat Safely on Telegram</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-chat-safely-on-telegram/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-chat-safely-on-telegram</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 14:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles&#038;p=466</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Despite its popularity in many countries, the messaging app Telegram is not as secure as most of its users think. For starters, regular Telegram chats are not end-to-end encrypted. While the app does offer a way for two people to chat through an end-to-end encrypted channel, this option is not default. Nor is it available [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-chat-safely-on-telegram/">How to Chat Safely on Telegram</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Despite its popularity in many countries, the messaging app Telegram is not as secure as most of its users think. For starters, regular Telegram chats are not end-to-end encrypted. While the app does offer a way for two people to chat through an end-to-end encrypted channel, this option is not default. Nor is it available for group chats. Telegram also has access to all of its users’ contacts and collects their metadata, including IP addresses and details about their devices. Finally, group chats and channels on Telegram are not particularly secure.</p>
<p>If you choose to stay on Telegram despite these risks, the safest way to message someone on the app is by using Secret Chats and setting the messages to self-destruct shortly after being read.</p>
<h2>Use Secret Chats</h2>
<p>The best way to protect your messages on Telegram is to use one-on-one Secret Chats that are end-to-end encrypted. As mentioned above, Secret Chats are not the default chat option on Telegram.</p>
<p>To start a Secret Chat, select the contact with whom you want to chat and open their profile by tapping the user’s image in the header.</p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-467 aligncenter" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user.jpg" alt="Choosing a user on Telegram for additional chat features." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-user-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Tap the three-dotted symbol next to the user’s name and select <strong>Start Secret Chat</strong> in the drop-down menu.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-469" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat.jpg" alt="Starting a secret chat with a friend on Telegram." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Confirm the selection by tapping <strong>Start</strong>. Once you start a Secret Chat, you will see a lock icon next to the user’s name in the header of the chat.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-470" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-confirm.jpg" alt="Confirm to start a secret chat on Telegram." width="1400" height="1400" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-confirm.jpg 1400w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-confirm-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-confirm-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-confirm-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-confirm-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-secret-chat-confirm-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1400px) 100vw, 1400px" /></p>
<h2>Set a self-destruct timer</h2>
<p>To set messages in a Secret Chat to self-destruct after being read, open the chat in which you want to use this option. What sets Secret Chats apart from regular chats on Instagram is a lock icon next to a user’s name, with both the lock symbol and the name appearing in green. Once you open the Secret Chat, tap the clock icon (in the Message field on iOS or top bar on Android).</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-471" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer.jpg" alt="Accessing the self-destruct timer on Telegram." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-timer-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Select the desired time limit (from one second to one week). You will see the time limit set for the Secret Chat in the Message field. <img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-472" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct.jpg" alt="Setting the self-destruct time on Telegram." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-self-destruct-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>The self-destruct timer starts ticking the moment the message is displayed on the recipient’s screen (you will see two check marks under the message). As soon as the time runs out, the message disappears from both devices.</p>
<p>Please note that the self-destruct timer in Secret Chats will not have any effect on messages that were sent <strong>before</strong> the timer was set.</p>
<h2>Watch out for screenshots</h2>
<p>Telegram tries to detect screenshots and notify people using Secret Chats when a screenshot is taken.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-473" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot.jpg" alt="Screenshot detection and notification on Telegram." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/telegram-screenshot-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Unfortunately, this function does not always work on some Android devices. You can also never know if a person you are messaging takes pictures of their screen with a different device. So, do not send private, confidential or sensitive messages to someone whom you do not trust fully.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-chat-safely-on-telegram/">How to Chat Safely on Telegram</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Send Vanishing Messages on WhatsApp</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-send-vanishing-messages-on-whatsapp/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=how-to-send-vanishing-messages-on-whatsapp</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 14:53:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles&#038;p=475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>WhatsApp is generally a very secure messaging app that offers end-to-end encryption by default. However, it is less focused on user privacy than messengers like Signal or Wire. Although WhatsApp cannot access your encrypted messages, it collects a lot of metadata (the who, when and where information about your messaging) on you, as well as [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-send-vanishing-messages-on-whatsapp/">How to Send Vanishing Messages on WhatsApp</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WhatsApp is generally a very secure messaging app that offers end-to-end encryption by default. However, it is less focused on user privacy than messengers like Signal or Wire. Although WhatsApp cannot access your encrypted messages, it collects a lot of metadata (the who, when and where information about your messaging) on you, as well as your contacts and information about your device. WhatsApp shares this information with its parent company Facebook. Facebook then uses this information for commercial purposes and shares it with partners. In the event of data breach, all of this sensitive data could be compromised.</p>
<p>If you choose to stay on WhatsApp despite these risks, the app offers a very reliable and secure messaging platform protected by end-to-end encryption. You can further protect your conversations and the files you share on the app by setting messages to disappear automatically and by sharing photos and videos that vanish as soon as they are seen by the recipient.<br />
Set messages to vanish<br />
You can set messages in an individual chat to disappear after seven days. If you enable this setting, WhatsApp will securely delete chats from your phone and that of the recipient seven days after they are sent. Unfortunately, the seven-day option is the only one that WhatsApp currently provides.</p>
<p>To enable disappearing messages in an individual WhatsApp chat, open the chat and tap the contact’s name. Scroll down and select <strong>Disappearing Messages</strong>. If prompted, tap <strong>Continue</strong> to confirm the selection.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-482" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend.jpg" alt="Selecting a friend and then scrolling down to find Disappearing Messages under Contact Info in Whatsapp." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-friend-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-481" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info.jpg" alt="Disappearing Messages option under Contact Info in Whatsapp." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-contact-info-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Select On. When you enable disappearing messages, you will see a notification in the chat. You will also see a clock icon displayed on the contact’s profile image.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-480" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages.jpg" alt="Enabling Disappearing Messages in Whatsapp." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-disappearing-messages-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Please note that enabling disappearing messages will not have any effect on messages that were sent <strong>before</strong> the setting was enabled. It is also worth remembering that disappearing messages will not prevent the person you are chatting with from forwarding your messages or keeping them by taking screenshots or saving media files.</p>
<h2>Using “view once” feature</h2>
<p>The “view once” feature allows you to set photos and videos to disappear after they are seen. This feature gives you more control over your privacy than when you send media files in a regular way. After the recipient opens the media file, it gets deleted as soon as they navigate away from it. If the recipient does not open the file, it expires and vanishes after two weeks.</p>
<p>You know that a message is a “view once” file when the preview is hidden and a large “1” is displayed instead. “View ones” media files cannot be shared or saved to a device.</p>
<p>To send a “view once” file, open an individual or group chat and tap <strong>Attach</strong> (a + icon on iPhone or a staple icon on an Android device). Select an existing photo or video on your device. Alternatively, you can tap <strong>Camera</strong> and take a photo or record a video that will not be saved on your device.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-479" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo.jpg" alt="Choosing a photo to send selecting the Photo and Video Library option in Whatsapp." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-choose-photo-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Tap “1” in the Message field. You will see a notification saying “Photo set to view once”, and the “1” icon in the message field will turn blue.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-478" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once.jpg" alt="Number 1 appearing as an indicator in the text box when a photo is set to view once before being sent in Whatsapp." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-view-once-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Tap <strong>Send</strong>.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-477" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view.jpg" alt="How a photo that is set to view once appears with the number 1 appearing next to it in a Whatsapp chat." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-view-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>You will see an Opened receipt in the chat once the recipient has seen the photo or video.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-476" src="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened.jpg" alt="How a photo that is set to view once appears after viewed in a Whatsapp chat." width="1600" height="1600" srcset="https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened.jpg 1600w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened-300x300.jpg 300w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened-150x150.jpg 150w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened-768x768.jpg 768w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://cyber-star.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/whatsapp-photo-opened-1200x1200.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></p>
<p>Please note that using the “view once” feature does not prevent the recipient from taking a screenshot or screen recording of the media file when it is first opened. So, do not send private, confidential or sensitive photos or videos to someone whom you do not trust fully.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/how-to-send-vanishing-messages-on-whatsapp/">How to Send Vanishing Messages on WhatsApp</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Secure Messaging Apps: Online Course</title>
		<link>https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/secure-messaging-apps/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=secure-messaging-apps</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[berker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 04:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cyber-star.org/?post_type=cs-articles&#038;p=107</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/secure-messaging-apps/">Secure Messaging Apps: Online Course</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/cs-articles/secure-messaging-apps/">Secure Messaging Apps: Online Course</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://cyber-star.org/">CyberSTAR</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
